Guide to the Duke Endowment Reference Collection, 1964-ongoing
University Archives Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Duke Endowment Reference collection 1964-ongoing
University Archives, Duke University
Duke University. University Archives
1.5 Linear Feet 500 Items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
Provenance
The Duke Endowment Reference Collection was compiled from a variety of sources by the University Archives for use in reference and research.
Historical Note
The Duke Endowment is a common law charitable trust that began its legal existence on December 11, 1924, when James Buchanan Duke signed the Indenture, which established a $40 million dollar endowment whose mission is to serve the people of North Carolina and South Carolina by supporting selected programs of higher education, health care, children's welfare, and spiritual life. Market Value of Endowment Assets as of Dec. 31, 2006: Approximately $2.9 billion.
Collection Overview
The Duke Endowment Reference Collection contains addresses, clippings, ephemera, news releases, information on the Duke Endowment archives housed in the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library at Duke University, as well as various newsletters, reports, and yearbooks concerning the Duke Endowment and Duke Power. This collection was compiled from a variety of sources by the University Archives for use in reference and research
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Duke Endowment
Duke University -- History
Duke Power Company
Endowments -- North Carolina
Related Material
Robert F. Durden Reference Collection, circa 1965-2001.
University Archives, Duke University.
William Preston Few records and papers, 1814-1971 (bulk 1911-1940).
University Archives, Duke University.
The Duke Endowment Archives: records, 1902 - [ongoing] (bulk [1920s]-[1990s]) [manuscript].
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library.
Papers, 1924-1928. [Betty Dailey]
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library.
Papers, 1927-1998. [Clyde, Paul Hibbert, 1896-]
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library.
Contents of Collection
- Container List, 1964-ongoing, 1 Box
  - Addresses (delivered at the 8th, 9th, and 10th Anniversaries of the Duke Endowment) (Box 1)
  - Addresses c.2
  - Clippings, ephemera, and news releases (4 folders)
  - Committee on Educational Institutions, 1965; 1967
  - Committee on Educational Institutions, 1970-1971
  - Committee on Educational Institutions, 1972-1973
  - Committee on Educational Institutions, 1974-1975
  - Committee on Educational Institutions c.2 (2 folders)
  - Duke Endowment Archives
  - Duke Endowment Archives, Inventory
  - Duke Endowment and _____
  - Duke Power Archives, a Chronology of Duke Power
  - Indenture of James B. Duke establishing The Duke Endowment (10 copies)
  - Issues' newsletter, c.2 and c.3 (c.1 is cataloged)
  - Questions and Answers, 1987-1997 [pamphlet]
  - Questions and Answers c.2
  - Reports - Annual Report, 1991
  - Reports - Annual Report, 2005
  - Reports - Report of the Secretary, 1964
  - Reports - Report of the Treasurer, 1964
  - Yearbook, no. 3, 25, 26
  - James B. Duke Memorial Volume, signed by Trustees of the Duke Endowment at a meeting held 1925 Oct. 27